Kaiju No. 8.
怪兽8号
I picked up strange human-like traits from him.
感觉它有如人类般的不协调感
In addition,
再加上
No. 9 can speak and look like a human.
会说人话又能变身成人类的9号
What's going on with kaiju?
怪兽究竟发生了什么事？
Vice-Captain!
副队长
I'm going to work hard to contribute!
我会努力成为战力的
I'll keep my expectations at 1%.
我姑且对你有1%的期待
I want to meet his expectations.
我得回应这份期待
Finally, my first step!
很好，总算踏出第一步了
I'll go back to sleep to prepare for tomorrow.
回去睡觉好好面对明天吧
Resting is a part of work, too!
休息也是工作的一环
Operation Room! What's going on?
作战室，发生什么事？
Several dozen kaiju have appeared inside the base!
基地内出现数十只怪兽！
Judging from the situation,
根据现状判断
Kaiju are attacking from the sky!
怪兽可能是从空中袭击！
Estimated power is 6.1.
推定强度6.1
6.3, 6.2, 6.5… All the kaiju are…
6.3、6.2、6.5 所有个体…
A kaiju?
怪兽？
Honju class!
…都是主兽级
It's Hoshina. Captain Ashiro isn't present.
我是保科，由于亚白队长不在
So, I'll be giving out instructions.
由我代为进行指挥
All night security officers, get into combat.
夜间警备队全员开始应战
Send out a dispatch to off-duty officers as well.
非值班的队员也紧急出动
-Everyone, get prepared for combat. -Roger!
-各自做好战斗准备 -了解
Try to lure them to the training ground.
尽可能把怪兽引到演习场
Don't let a single kaiju escape the base!
绝对别让它们跑出基地！
No damage reports from the outside.
话虽如此，还没收到外面的损害报告
Could it be…
该不会…
their target is this base?
它们的目标是这个基地？
What the hell's going on?
这是怎么回事？
The base is a sea of fire!
基地陷入火海了！
Wyvern-type Kaiju！
翼龙系怪兽！
Those are troublesome.
麻烦的家伙出现了
Wyvern-types?
翼龙系？
If so, there's something wrong with them!
那样的话，这些家伙很奇怪啊！
Place the officers good at shooting in the center.
擅长狙击的队员往中央集火
-Let's lure them and shoot them down. -Roger!
-我们将怪兽引过来击落 -了解！
Vice-Captain!
副队长！
-Kafka, you're safe? -Yes, sir.
-卡夫卡，你没事吧？ -是
-Something bothers me about these kaiju. -Report.
-更重要的是我发现奇怪的事情 -报告吧
About ten or so wyvern-type kaiju are reported in a year,
报告说翼龙系怪兽 每年大概会出现十只左右
and they all share a common trait.
而且全部都有相同的特征
They only act on their own.
它们都是单独行动
But these guys are acting as a group.
但这些家伙却成群结队出现
Yeah. That means there's only one possibility.
我懂了，能想到的原因只有一个
There's a force strong enough to lead these prideful wyvern-types.
力量强大到能够 率领高傲的翼龙系怪兽
Something acting with purpose,
有目的地的行动
with high intellect.
并具备智慧…
They have a super powerful leader.
它们当中有着超强大的首领
Target found.
发现目标
I'm hanging up, Kafka.
先挂了，卡夫卡
Are you the strongest one in this base?
这个基地最强的是你吗？
This one speaks human, too?
这家伙也会说话？
Captain's not here, so I guess it would be me.
队长不在，所以…就是我了
I see.
这样啊
It's decided, then. You'll be my prey.
那就决定了，你是我的猎物
Estimated fortitude of the honju has been calculated! 8.3!
主兽推定规模出来了！8.3！
It's a Daikaiju Class!
是大怪兽级别！
-Ikaruga, can you hear me? -Yes, sir!
-斑鸠，听得到吗？ -是
You take the lead to defeat the yoju.
你负责指挥对付余兽
First priority is civilian harm prevention
首要任务是防止损害扩大到民间
-and protecting the main office! -Roger!
-并保护行政大楼的运作 -了解！
I'll take care of the honju.
主兽由我…
You dodged it, huh? You've passed.
躲开了吗？你及格了
I have to be the one to take care of this one.
这家伙必须由我杀掉
All right.
很好
Now, the annihilation
那就正式开始…
has officially begun.
歼灭敌人吧
The yoju are responding to him?
余兽在回应它？
I knew it. This base was the target.
果然目标是基地吗？
He's crazy strong, like a meteor!
威力夸张地像陨石一样
If I take that attack head-on, it's the end of me.
被打中一下就完了
His exterior's harder than No. 8!
比8号还硬！
Shoot!
开火！
He's unharmed!
毫发无伤？
Retreat! Shooters, change the bullets to Oscillator Rounds.
快撤退！ 狙击手将子弹换成重震动弹！
Don't shoot the front!
不能攻击正面！
This voice… Is this Hibino?
这声音，是日比野吗？
Aim for the back. This kaiju
要瞄准背部，这些家伙
is the same type recorded in the Year 03.
跟03年记载的怪兽是同一种
-Senpai? -Is that Old Man?
-前辈？ -是大叔吗？
I couldn't reach you. I was worried.
刚刚联络不上你，我们还很担心
Sorry. I was talking to Vice-Captain.
抱歉，我在跟副队长讲话
Forget that. Aim for the back!
总之要攻击背面，瞄准背面攻击！
They're often attacked when flying, so their frontal skin is tougher.
它们飞行时容易被攻击正面 因此正面的皮很硬
Their core is in their back.
核心的位置应该在背面
Their backs have minimal toughness
相对地，为了减轻体重
to maintain their light weight for flight!
背面只有最低限度的防护
Great work, Hibino!
干得好，日比野！
Split in two. Keep them distracted in the front and shoot the back!
兵分两路，一人从正面吸引注意力 一人从怪兽背后射击
Roger!
了解
-Stay back. -I'll take the lead, thanks.
-后退 -前面是我的
I'll be the bait.
我来当诱饵
Go around, Haruichi! You owe me one!
阳一，绕过去，你欠我一次
As expected of him.
真是厉害
Combat Power, Maximum Release!
战力全解放！
The kaiju are working together?
怪兽竟然会合作？
-We can't get behind them! -Same here.
-不行，没办法绕到背后 -这边也失败了
-There was kaiju interception. -What?
-有怪兽妨碍进攻 -怎么会？
What should we do?
该怎么办？
If we can't get behind them, how can we shoot their backs?
没办法绕到背后要怎么攻击？
-There's another way. -Shinomiya?
-还有一个方法啊 -四之宫？
What is it?
还有什么方法…
I could…
由我来…
overtake them from the front…
用压倒性的力量
with my immense power!
从正面打穿就好啦！
A weapon made especially for me?
我的专用武器？
I thought only captain-ranked officers got them.
不是队长级才有吗？
That's usually the case.
通常是这样
In light of the situation, we decided to give you one.
但这次是为了因应现况
The strength and number of kaiju is abnormal this year.
今年怪兽的强度和数量都不同以往
We've decided to add you to the core force of the base,
因此我们决定让战斗力高居第三的你
as someone with the third-highest combat power.
担任主力之一
Shinomiya. Starting now, annihilate kaiju as the Number Three,
四之宫，以后你要作为 队长、副队长之后的第三大战力
after the captain and vice-captain.
将怪兽歼灭
The power's okay, considering it's a prototype.
以试作品来说，威力还不错
If I had any complaints,
要挑毛病的话
it's that it looks too rugged and doesn't suit me.
就是太粗犷了，不太适合我呢
She crushed it from the front!
竟然从正面打倒了！
All right, kaiju.
好了，怪兽们
Now that I'm on the battleground,
有我在的战场
no more playing around.
你们别想继续胡作非为
Its main material is the uniorgan
这把武器的主要素材
of a honju that was neutralized in Shinagawa two years ago.
是前年品川所讨伐的本兽单器官
If you turn on the power with the trigger, it'll release a shock wave.
扣下扳机就能让武器通电 发出冲击波
Application one,
应用方式一
release shock wave to the back while it's in motion.
行动时朝后方发出冲击波
Speed up!
加速！
Squadron-Style Ax Technique Number One - Falling Thunder!
队式斧术1式，落雷！
Application two,
应用方式二
release shock wave to the front during collision.
接战时朝前方发出冲击波
More force!
猛击！
Technique Number Two - Water Skimmer.
队式斧术2式，水切！
Wow!
好强！
It doesn't suit me, my ass.
还说什么不适合你？
It's the perfect match for your aggressive and dominating personality.
对性格好战又强势的你来说 再适合不过了
Next up!
好，下一只
Above?
上面？
Freeze Rounds?
冻结弹？
-Reno! -Stay alert. They're attacking from above.
-雷诺！ -四之宫，别大意，上方也会有怪兽
Like I'd let you fly!
别想飞起来！
He's doing well fighting against such a high-level kaiju.
他竟然也能对付这种等级的怪兽
Technique Number Three - Half Moon!
斧术3式，半月！
-All right! -Reno.
-好耶 -雷诺
I'll let you back me up.
我允许你来掩护我
If you can keep up, that is.
前提是你能跟上的话
Bring it on!
正合我意
All right, let's join forces and stir up the enemy.
我们就当游击队来扰乱敌人吧
You hear that?
听到了吧？
Yeah. Creating a disturbance with only two people? As expected of Shinomiya.
听到了，只靠两人来扰乱敌方 真像四之宫的风格
We can't be left behind by them.
我们可不能置之不理啊
In that case, we'll…
那样的话，我们…
Get behind the enemy after they've been lured by Shinomiya!
绕到被四之宫吸引的怪兽后面！
Squad Shinomiya will break up the kaiju coordination!
四之宫分队会扰乱怪兽的合作
We're continuing with our plan! Split into two and shoot their backs!
继续原本的作战 兵分两路朝背后射击！
Sounds like Shinomiya will take care of that.
看来四之宫有发挥作用
The problem is…
问题是…
this guy!
这家伙
He's strong.
好强
Not only that, he's…
不仅是强大，这家伙…
enjoying the fight.
很享受战斗
-Okonogi-chan, release Gate Three! -Roger!
-小此木，打开3号大门 -了解
NUMBER THREE
（第三大门）
He's expressing emotion beyond what kaiju are capable of.
这很明显不是怪兽会有的感情
We opened that gate for nothing! Doors are expensive, you know!
开门完全没有意义嘛，那扇门很贵耶
Where is he?
它在哪？
No one can fight this well against me.
能和我打这么久
Not even most kaiju.
就算是怪兽也没几个
I'd love to eat you and use you for sustenance.
务必要让我吃了你，来为我所用
Vice-Captain!
副队长！
You're really strong, you know.
你真的挺能打的
Sorry, Okonogi-chan.
抱歉，小此木
It's an emergency. I didn't have time to ask for permission.
事出紧急，恕我省略申请
At least in this training ground,
在演习场的话
I won't get other officers involved if I get serious.
就算使出全力 也不用担心会牵连队员了
Combat Power Maximum Release, 92%.
战力全解放，92%
Let's begin this neutralization, shall we?
那么，开始讨伐怪兽吧
So powerful!
威力好强
Will I not make it?
来得及吗？
I could do a partial transformation!
如果是部分变身的话！
Hibino-san?
日比野？
-Are you hurt, Minase? -I'm okay, thanks!
-水无瀬，你没受伤吧？ -谢谢你
You've gotten better at using that suit!
你战斗服也用得很熟练了呢
I've become a general officer and all. I can manage this!
好歹我也是正式队员 这种程度当然会！
Behind you!
你后面！
Kikoru!
琪歌露！
-Kikorun! -Are you all right, Senpai?
-琪歌露 -你没事吧，前辈？
Reno and I are luring the kaiju.
雷诺和我会引开怪兽
Meanwhile, take care of the injured.
拜托你们趁机救助伤者了
Roger!
-了解！
Senpai.
前辈
Don't do something dangerous, okay?
请你千万不要乱来
You're a general officer now.
你已经是正式队员了
Have trust in the squad.
相信大家的力量吧
-Yeah! -I'll see you later!
-好！ -我先走一步
Wow!
好厉害
When did they learn to work so well together?
他们什么时候学会那样合作的？
Reporting! Platoon Nakanoshima has arrived!
报告！中之岛小队抵达现场
Sorry for the wait, Ikaruga!
久等啦，斑鸠
Platoon Ebina has also arrived! They're heading south to assist.
海老名小队也接续抵达现场 正在前往南方增援
Don't enjoy yourselves too much, kaiju!
别想再为所欲为了，这些怪兽
The off-duty senpai are all here!
是没有值班的前辈们 他们来帮忙了！
Squad Shinomiya and Platoon Wagatsuma have defeated two yoju!
四之宫分队、我妻小队击败两只余兽
This is Platoon Takao. We've completed the formation of the shooting squad.
这里是鹰尾小队，狙击部队编成完毕
We'll be using Freeze Rounds to attack the yoju in the sky.
开始用冻结弹攻击空中的余兽
This is Platoon Itakura. We've secured the storage area.
这里是板仓小队，已经守住仓库地区
We're beginning to push back, even in an emergency with the captain absent.
开始扳回劣势了 明明是没有队长指挥的紧急状况
-Minase. Let's go care for the injured! -Yeah!
-好，水无瀬，我们也快去救人吧 -好！
They're amazing.
好厉害
Not just Kikoru and Ichikawa, everyone is crazy strong.
不只是琪歌露和市川，大家都好厉害
This is the division I'm a part of.
这就是我所属的部队
This is…
这就是…
The Third Division!
第3部队！
You picked a fight with the wrong guys.
你挑错打架对手了呢
We'll be winning this one.
这场战斗，我们赢定了
He did it again. Same as the attack that took out this arm.
又来了，切断手臂的那一击也是这样
He is precise in slicing
他能够精准地…
the gap between my shells.
砍向甲壳间的缝隙
This is boring. It's a cheap trick.
这家伙好无聊，像这种把戏
Once I know where he's aiming, I can fight back.
只要知道他瞄准哪里，就能轻松应付
Hoshina-style Sword-Slay Technique Number Two,
保科流刀伐术2式
Cross Slasher.
交叉袭
Number Four,
4式
Wild Slasher!
乱袭！
Aiming for the gaps was just a diversion?
瞄准缝隙只是佯攻吗？
This is what real fighting is!
果然战斗就是得像这样！
Clashing face-to-face with an equal opponent!
跟旗鼓相当的对手正面交锋！
Equal!
旗鼓相当！
What?
咦？
Your core's smaller than expected.
没想到你的核心这么小
Number Six,
6式
Eightfold Slasher.
八重袭
He did it!
成功了！
-As expected of Vice-Captain! -You see that, kaiju?
-真不愧是副队长 -见识到了吧，怪兽！
-This is… -We're not done!
-这是… -还没完！
-Hibino-san? What's wrong? -I'm okay.
-日比野？怎么了吗？ -没，我没事
What's going on? I haven't transformed, but my perception's reacting.
怎么回事？ 我没变身，却能察觉怪兽的动静
Vice-Captain.
副队长…
He grew?
竟然巨大化了？
Was I unable to destroy his core because it changed position?
它错开了核心的位置 所以没能彻底破坏吗？
An ultra-high temperature vapor.
超高温的蒸汽…
I'm glad I lured him to the training ground.
把它引到演习场是正确的
A release of heat and an increase in fortitude!
随着放热，怪兽规模也上升了
This is…
这是…
Fortitude
怪兽规模…
9.0!
9.0！
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰